Ningna Wang

☑ ningna.wang@utdallas.edu | 🏠 ningnawang.github.io | 🖸 github.com/ningnawang | 🞓 Ningna Wang

Research Interests

My research interests broadly lie in **computer graphics**, **geometry processing**, and **3D shape analysis**. My current research direction focuses on **3D medial axis** computation and its applications. I aim to explore new representations and algorithms to process geometric data more efficiently and effectively. Additionally, I am also interested in exploring **aerial path planning** for 3D urban scene reconstruction.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science

University of Texas at Dallas | Dallas, Texas, USA

M.S. in Computer Science

Carnegie Mellon University | Pittsburgh, PA, USA

2019 - Present

2014 - 2016

B.S. in Computation Mathematics

Jilin University | Changchun, Jilin, China

2010 - 2014

Publications

MATTopo: Topology-preserving Medial Axis Transform with Restricted Power Diagram [Journal Track]

Ningna Wang, Hui Huang, Shibo Song, Bin Wang, Wenping Wang, Xiaohu Guo to appear in ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH Asia) (2024). 2024

NASM: Neural Anisotropic Surface Meshing [Conference Track]

Hongbo Li, Haikuan Zhu, Sikai Zhong, **Ningna Wang**, Cheng Lin, Xiaohu Guo, Shiqing Xin, Wenping Wang, Jing Hua, Zichun Zhong to appear in ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG/SIGGRAPH Asia) (2024). 2024

CWF: Consolidating Weak Features in High-quality Mesh Simplification [Journal Track]

Rui Xu, Longdu Liu, **Ningna Wang**, SM Chen, Shiqing Xin, Xiaohu Guo, Zichun Zhong, Taku Komura, Wenping Wang, Changhe Tu *ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH)* 43.4 (2024). ACM New York, NY, USA, 2024

Globally Consistent Normal Orientation for Point Clouds by Regularizing the Winding-Number Field [Best Paper Award] Rui Xu, Zhiyang Dou, Ningna Wang, Shiqing Xin, Shuangmin Chen, Mingyan Jiang, Xiaohu Guo, Wenping Wang, Changhe Tu ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH) (2023). ACM New York, NY, USA, 2023

S3DS: Self-supervised Learning of 3D Skeletons from Single View Images
Jianwei Hu, **Ningna Wang**, Baorong Yang, Gang Chen, Xiaohu Guo, Bin Wang *ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACM MM)* (2023). 2023

Point2MM: Learning medial mesh from point clouds

Mengyuan Ge, Junfeng Yao, Zhonggui Chen, Baorong Yang, **Ningna Wang**, Xiaohu Guo *Computers & Graphics (Proceedings of CAD/Graphics)* (2023). 2023

Computing Medial Axis Transform with Feature Preservation via Restricted Power Diagram [Journal Track]

Ningna Wang, Bin Wang, Wenping Wang, Xiaohu Guo

ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH Asia) 41.6 (2022) pp. 1-18. ACM New York, NY, USA, 2022

IMMAT: Mesh reconstruction from single view images by medial axis transform prediction

Jianwei Hu, Gang Chen, Baorong Yang, **Ningna Wang**, Xiaohu Guo, Bin Wang *Computer-Aided Design (CAD)* 150 (2022) p. 103304. Elsevier, 2022

Computer Anded Design (CAD) 130 (2022) p. 103304. Elseviel, 2022

A method of realistic leaves modeling based on point cloud

Yinghui Wang, Wen Hao, Gang Wang, Xiaojuan Ning, Jing Tang, Zhenghao Shi, **Ningna Wang**, Minghua Zhao *Proceedings of the 12th ACM SIGGRAPH International Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and Its Applications in Industry*, 2013

Invited Talks_

Computing Medial Axis Transform with Feature Preservation via Restricted Power Diagram

ACM SIGGRAPH ASIA 2022

Center for Digital Media Computing, Xiamen University

MATTopo: Topology-preserving Medial Axis Transform with Restricted Power Diagram

Visual Computing Research Center, Shenzhen University Center for Digital Media Computing, Xiamen University Daegu, South Korea, Dec 2022 Online, Nov 2022

> Shenzhen, China, Nov 2023 Online, Jan 2024

JULY 31, 2024

Work Experience

Department of Computer Science, University of Texas at Dallas

Dallas, Texas, USA

Research Assistant | Advisor: Dr. Xiaohu Guo

Aug 2019 - Present

- Developed a complete framework for computing the medial axis of 3D CAD meshes with **sharp-features preservation**.
- Developed a novel topology-preserving 3D medial axis computation framework based on volumetric restricted power diagram (RPD).
- Researched on new learning-based methods for mesh reconstruction via 3D skeleton prediction from single view images or point clouds.
- Developed a new method for estimating **globally consistent normal orientations** for a raw point cloud.
- Studied a smooth mesh simplification functional that simultaneously consolidates weak features in a high-quality mesh.

Teaching Assistant 2020, 2021, 2022

- Built starter code for all course projects in UTD CS6323 Computer Animation and Gaming and CS6366 Computer Graphics.
- Held office hours and graded homework for graphics-related courses.

Shenzhen University

Shenzhen, Guangdong, China

Research Intern | Advisor: Dr. Hui Huang

Oct-Dec 2023

• Conducted research on **aerial path planning** for drone trajectory and image capturing, efficiently yielding high-quality 3D scene reconstructions with maximum scene information and minimum flying cost.

Booking.com B.V. Amsterdam, Netherlands

Senior Software Engineer Core Software Engineer Nov. 2018 - July 2019 Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2018

• [System Design and Development] Responsible for the design, development, and continued operation of the **hotel availability search system**, which handles thousands of incoming hotel search requests per second.

- [Production Infrastructure Optimization] Significantly enhanced system stability and scalability by distributing hotel availabilities using **jump consistent hashing**, a fast consistent hash algorithm with no storage and minimal memory requirements.
- [Cross-Functional Collaboration] Collaborated seamlessly with product-side engineers and partner-side engineers to ensure the successful development and delivery of the search system.

The Priceline Group Inc.

Amsterdam, Netherlands | Seattle, WA, USA

Graduate Software Engineer

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- [System Design] Developed a **hotel inventory management system** with a wealth of features, including property listing, yield management, and revenue analytics.
- [Feature Optimization] Implemented and experimented new features for the **Genius loyalty program** for various discounts and travel rewards.

Awards_

2024	First Place CAST STAR Award (1/16 teams), CAST-STEM Bridge Summer Camp	USA
2023	Best Paper Award, SIGGRAPH 2023	USA
2013	Honorable Mention, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	USA
2011	First Prize Scholarship & Outstanding Student, Jilin University (2011-2013)	China
2010	Second Prize Scholarship & Outstanding Student, Jilin University	China

Review Service __

Conference	ACM SIGGRAPH ACM SIGGRAPH Asia	2024
Conference	International Conference on Geometric Modeling and Processing (GMP)	2024
Conference	Pacific Graphics IPC	2023
Journal	Graphical Models	2024
Journal	IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)	2022

Teaching_

Teaching Assistant	UTD Clark Summer Research Program	2024 Summer
Teaching Assistant	CAST-STEM Bridge Summer Camp	2024 Summer
Teaching Assistant	UTD CS6323 Computer Animation and Gaming	2022 Fall
Teaching Assistant	UTD CS6366 Computer Graphics	2021 Spring
Teaching Assistant	UTD CS6334 Virtual Reality	2020 Spring
Teaching Assistant	UTD CS4347 Database Systems	2022 Fall, 2021 Spring
Teaching Assistant	UTD CS4332 Introduction to Programming Video Games	2019 Fall

July 31, 2024 2